<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentations | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/presentations/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/presentations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Presentations</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/presentations/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating presentations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/creating-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/creating-presentations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-formulate-a-topic&#34;&gt;1. Formulate a topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to listen to an interlocutor who jumps from one to another, so the presentation should have only one topic. Otherwise, you will get a long story about nothing. The topic should be narrow enough to offer a solution to the problem at the end. Narrow down the topic until the presentation can be summarized in ten short paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to determine a good topic - it itself suggests the structure of the speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-define-a-goal&#34;&gt;2. Define a goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation changes the current picture of the world. For example, people are beginning to take care of the environment or run for a new smartphone. The goal does not have to be ambitious, the main thing is specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation goal starts with the question: what do I want to change in the behavior of listeners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-think-about-the-scenario&#34;&gt;3. Think about the scenario&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the presentation is what you want to change in the listener&amp;rsquo;s head, and the script is how you will arrive at that change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re making up a story. The listener needs to be intrigued, come up with an interesting hero, guide him through difficulties to a successful ending. This is the basic structure of any text and presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-show-examples&#34;&gt;4. Show examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less theory, more life. Show how your product works and how people use it. See how they do it on Kickstarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real stories of people, screenshots of programs and live photos of the product look more convincing than dry text and photos from photo stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-alternate-slides&#34;&gt;5. Alternate slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation is like text. If the text consists of sentences of the same length and the same type, it will be boring to read. There is no rhythm. Therefore, alternate text slides and slides with images, add graphs. Sometimes you can make a joke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-tell-me-what-to-do-next&#34;&gt;6. Tell me what to do next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bad speech ends like this: &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s it, now the questions.&amp;rdquo; So you leave the listener alone with his thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation gives clear instructions on what to do next. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a call to action. At the end, you can once again go through the conclusions, emphasize the main thesis or say where to get additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End with instructions or output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-fewer-colors&#34;&gt;7. Fewer colors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presentation should have 1-2 primary colors. For example, for background, text, and icons. Follow the chosen sequence and do not change colors unnecessarily. It is quite difficult to choose colors on your own, especially if you are not a designer. If you&amp;rsquo;re making a corporate presentation, use brand colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are no corporate colors, use color selection sites. There are ready-made combinations that are pleasant to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-more-contrast&#34;&gt;8. More contrast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White on blue can look nice on your computer with a Retina screen. But if you have to show the presentation through the projector, the text will not be read. Therefore, use contrasting colors. The biggest contrast: black and white. The rest can be checked using the contrast check service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-fewer-fonts&#34;&gt;9. Fewer fonts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One font is enough to create a presentation. Take a modern sans-serif font: Open Sans, Roboto, PT Sans (these fonts are free to use). These are simple fonts that are easy to read. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to check: step away from the screen and try to read the headline. If it&amp;rsquo;s easy to read, you guessed it. Accents can be made by changing the font weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-the-rule-of-thirds&#34;&gt;10. The Rule of Thirds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rule of creating presentations helps to arrange objects on the slide so that the eye immediately highlights the most important. Divide the slide into thirds lengthwise and wide. Place significant objects at intersections. Significant objects are headings and illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;11-texts-shorter&#34;&gt;11. Texts shorter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One slide, one thought. Such a slide is easy to read and remember. If you speak in public, it will keep the audience&amp;rsquo;s attention. Exactly how much text will be on the slide depends on the size of the audience. If a person reads a presentation on a screen, a paragraph of text will not scare him. If you are speaking in front of an audience of a hundred people, it will be difficult to read more than ten words on a slide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-calculate-how-many-slides-should-be-in-the-presentation&#34;&gt;12. Calculate how many slides should be in the presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple rule that can be taken as a basis for creating presentations is one slide per minute. If your presentation is designed for 30 minutes, then the optimal number of slides is also 30!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;13-add-images&#34;&gt;13. Add images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos and icons help to reveal the content, but should not replace it. If you find a beautiful photo &amp;ldquo;in the topic&amp;rdquo; that does not help to reveal the idea, do not use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to look for free images - Tilda&amp;rsquo;s instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where to look for free icons - Tilda&amp;rsquo;s instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to choose an image that will strengthen the thought - an article by Maxim Ilyakhov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;14-make-friends-slides&#34;&gt;14. Make friends slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the presentation, all elements should be friends, that is, be of the same type. Then it is perceived easily, because it meets expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make several templates for each type of slide: a slide with text, with an image, a graph. Then just duplicate the slides and change only the text and images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A presentation where the same type of elements occupy the same place on each slide looks neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resource&#34;&gt;Resource&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tilda.education/articles-how-to-create-presentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://tilda.education/articles-how-to-create-presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
